

Arda Sener

Nationality: German Date of birth: 20/12/1996 Gender: Male

Companies Company C

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/arda-sener-7130131ba

• Home: Von-Reuter.Str. 10A, 80997 Munich (Germany)

ABOUT ME

I am a highly motivated Robotics, Cognition, Intelligence MS student at the Technical University of Munich. Especially working and researching in the field of machine learning are among my strengths. I enjoy tackling problems in the areas of data preprocessing, neural networks, and optimization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Masterand

Audi AG [11/2022 - Current]

City: Ingolstadt **Country:** Germany

Topic: Detecting driving factors for KPI calculation in GoldenAlgo dataset.

Research assistant for the conception of neural networks

Fraunhofer IIS EZRT [06/2021 - 11/2022]

City: Fürth, Nuremberg **Country:** Germany

Continuing research on my bachelor's thesis.

Working student for programming tasks cyberpromote GmbH [03/2021 - 05/2021]

City: Munich

Country: Germany

Continuation of the work from the previous internship

Bachelorand

Fraunhofer IIS EZRT [10/2020 - 03/2021]

City: Fürth

Country: Germany

Topic: Design of deep neural networks for input data from multimodal imaging sensor systems to determine the value of printed circuit boards in recycling.

Mandatory internship

cyberpromote GmbH [07/2020 - 11/2020]

City: Munich

Country: Germany

Writing Google Ads scripts and creating reports with Excel macros were very big projects in this internship. Also, an important analytics tool was created with a Python script.

Working student for the CATS-Flexible System

Siemens AG [11/2019 - 05/2020]

City: Nuremberg
Country: Germany

General programming tasks, such as updating source codes, were part of the daily work. The handling of the internal Git servers was taught intensively. In addition, programming with Bash scripts and C# was important for working with the CATS-flexible workbench.

Internship abroad in the field of nanotechnology

University of Utah [08/2019 – 09/2019]

City: Salt Lake City **Country:** United States

The project of this internship was to build a very thin camera. My main task was mainly to program the camera (installation on Raspberry Pi). The main innovation here was that the thin lens was made of metamaterials, which had to be attached to the camera. I also provided support for other, smaller projects.

Working student - programming activities

Fraunhofer-Gesellschaft IIS [05/2018 – 04/2019]

City: Nuremberg
Country: Germany

Support in the implementation of an algorithm for the automatic calibration of antennas from Matlab in C++ as well as the creation of a simulation tool for distance measurements to test this algorithm. In addition, smaller tasks such as sorting measured values or literature research were also mastered.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master of Science in Robotics, Cognition, Intelligence

Technical University of Munich [04/2021 – Current]

Address: Arcisstraße 21, 80333 Munich (Germany)

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics and Physics

Georg-Simon-Ohm Hochschule Nuremberg [10/2017 – 04/2021]

Address: Keßlerplatz 12, 90489 Nuremberg (Germany)

Final grade: 1,8

Thesis: Konzeption von tiefen neuronalen Netzen für Eingangsdaten aus multimodalen bildgebenden

Sensorsystemen zur Wertbestimmung von Leiterplatten im Recycling

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): German

Other language(s):

English Turkish

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2 LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programmierung und Programmiersprachen

Python / C# / MATLAB / Pycharm / C++ / Bash Shell Scripting / Maple / Mathematica / MS Visual Studio / Grundken ntnisse XML, XSL und X-Path / Fl Studio (DAW) / Visual Basic for Applications (VBA)

Dokumenten - und Kommunikationsanwendungen

google docs / Microsoft Office(Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Powerpoint, Microsoft Access, Microsoft Word / Sehr guter Umgang mit Kommunikationstools als Anwender (z.B. Zoom, Cisco WebEx, Skype)

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B

VOLUNTEERING

Team member at Phoenix TUM

[Munich, 28/04/2021 - Current]

Member of the "Lane Recognition" group in the "Machine Learning" group. We research and implement new algorithms for lane recognition. Organizing and coordinating Phoenix's autonomous driving team was part of my responsibilities as team leader.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Scholarship for education and training abroad

DAAD [19/03/2019]

I was awarded a fellowship in Utah. The work location was the University of Utah and the work took place from 08/01/2019 - 09/28/2019.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Play instruments

Playing guitar and saz (Turkish cultural instrument).

Recording own music with FL Studio.

Sport

Climbing, running and boxing are among the main activities.